

PHP Head of technical seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Solution Architecture, Solution Design, Software Testing, Quality Management, Process Optimization, Gap Analysis, Technical Documentation, Web Technologies, Web Services, PHP



Current Designation: Php Lead Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Airspace System Inc

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Chennai

Highest Degree: Other [Other]

Pref. Location: Chennai, Trivandrum

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: PHP Head of technical, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Solution Architecture, Solution Design, Software Testing, Quality Management, Process Optimization, Gap Analysis, Technical

Documentation, Web Technologies, Web Services

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 27-Jul-20 Last Modified: 3-Jun-20

Summary

Tech-savvy PHP Professional with nearly 12 years of exposure in extensive server-side & backend components of web applications, offering excellence in application works across browsers and devices to successfully integrate with third-party web services

Rich experience in Develop and Implement PHP Modules, implementation & Integrating Server-Side Code with Third-Party Modules right from Requirement Mapping, Documentation, Scoping, Gap Analysis, Application Development, Testing till Post Implementation Support

Possess rich functional experience of working on Implementation,

Configuration, Integration Testing, third-party Application

Programming Interfaces (APIs) to access data between servers and applications

Extensive project management experience, proficient in grasping the big picture, conceptualizing, developing, implementing solutions, partnering closely with business leaders & stakeholders to achieve higher levels of efficiency and effectiveness

Work Experience

Airspace System Inc as Php Lead Nov 2019 to Till Date

Working Php technical manager/Developer

Mayflower software private Limited as PHP Team Lead Jun 2017 to Nov 2019

Worked on Php application development, Team technical supports, functionality DB design and US customer handling

Quadrantfour Software Solutions as Team Lead -PHP Feb 2014 to May 2017

D - I - -

Presently managing 12 members team; building, testing and set up cutting-edge website applications in an efficient matter:

working with other developers to fill data acquisition requirements

Identifying and fix PHP, Node JS, Angular, Flutter, Java and scripting compatibility issues between a variety of platforms; test

websites on different browsers & mobile device browsers; correct problems identified by customer feedback Investigating and discovering architectural considerations, such as web usability, site performance and database design,

of the system design process; research and assess implementation alternatives for new application features

Collaborating and communicating with development teams and management to resolve conflicts, prioritize needs, choose solutions or develop content criteria

Developing procedures for ongoing website revision; recommending performance improvements; creating and refine style guidelines for website content; select design tools, programming languages or applications

Providing detailed explanations of website specifications, such as activities, software, product features, programming languages.

communication protocols and operating systems hardware and software

Defining service standards and guidelines as per global best practices, governance structures, best and documentation that

serve as benchmarks for excellent service delivery

Managing requirement, design, integration of components, addressing issues/escalations and providing production support to

existing systems

Participating in code walkthrough, troubleshooting and solution architecture

Preparing proposals, business presentations to clients and managing resource planning, technical direction, effort estimation.

tracking, risk management & mentoring

Providing post-implementation, application maintenance and enhancement support to the client with regard to the product /

software application

Leading, mentoring & monitoring the performance of team members to ensure efficiency in process operations

Developing competency among the team members; managing appraisal process across the levels; conducting interviews
to

recruit the right talent and resources

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Ponjesly College Of Engineering, Nagercoil in 2008

PG: Other (Other) in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
PHP, OOPS, Javascript, Basic Python	
Apache, Wamp & Xampp	
Laravel	
Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal	
MOODLE	
MAGENTO	
Jquery, AJAX, HTML5 & CSS,Javascript	
Bootstrap, JSON	
php, Python	
MYSQL, ORACLE	

https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1806859a625325cddbc5b5ea127f63a55d5a0b5049410917044341595... 1/22/2021

JSON & Restful API	
Notepad++, JIRA, pyCharm	
AWS	1 Year(s)
WINDOWS	14 Year(s)
GitHub	7 Year(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Tamil	Expert			
English	Expert			
Malayalam	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: Sales product Client: Rainmakerforce

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2017 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Project Location: USA Team Size: 15 Role: Project Leader Skill Used: Php, MySQL, Wordpress, Html5, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Javascript, Ajax,

Project Details: Its a US sales platform. Its contains lots of additional features like salesforce

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time